Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine
and for those of you
who have been following
this is the very last
episode of our 10 part series
about giving a presentation in English.
That's right, this is
part 10 where we are
going to receive questions
from the audience.
So this is called a Q&A session
or question and answer session.
Let's take a listen to our
dialogue, we'll be back in a moment.
Well everyone, I'm
sure you'd like to join
me in thanking Michael for what
was a really inspirational presentation.
Since here thanks
Michael, now I'm sure many
of you will be keen to ask some questions,
so I'd like to open up a Q&A session.
Please raise your hand if you have any
questions at all, yes Jan, let's go ahead.
Yes, thank you Jonathan,
I would just like to
go back to the comment
Mr. Ford made in regards
to our competitors,
particularly orange.
Now as you know, orange
has established themselves
as the market leader in
the high end laptop market.
How does Mr. Ford expect
to compete with a company
that has such a huge
reputation and huge resources?
Well Jan, first of all, thanks
for a very good question.
I think you have hit
the nail on the head
actually, orange are the global leaders
precisely because of their size and power.
But although we can't
compete in terms of
size, I believe we hold an advantage in
terms of dedication to customer service.
Yes, sidemit, this is
a David and Goliath
battle, but don't forget
who won that contest.
Mr. Ford, could you
elaborate on actual
technical details of the
X420 a little bit more?
I'd love to, but I think we're a
little pressed for time right now.
However, Jonathan is
all the technical specs
for you on the PowerPoint presentation,
which you can look over in your own time.
Mr. Ford, one final question.
Would you like to join me
for a game of golf this Sunday?
All right, we're back, so now let's take a
look at some words on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, at the beginning of
today's dialogue, Jonathan said,
"I'm sure many of you will be
keen to ask some questions."
What does this word keen mean?
All right, so to be
keen to do something,
which basically means
that you want to or would
like to do something,
right, are you keen?
Would you like to do it?
Are you interested in doing it?
Now this is a very British form
of addressing something, right?
That's right.
This is very British.
We don't really say
this as much in America,
but you can, people
will understand you.
I would say, "I'm sure many of you
would like to ask some questions.
" And so you could
say that both ways.
That's right, that's right.
Okay, so many people
want to ask questions
and Jonathan said, "So I'd like to
open it up to a Q and A session."
So the series of words here to open it up
to a Q and A session, what does that mean?
To open it up, it means the discussion.
So he would like to invite
people to ask questions.
So I'd like to open it up for questions.
I mean, I would like to give
you guys the opportunity to ask.
So to open up a discussion or
to open up a conversation, right?
I would like to open this up to you guys.
Okay.
Now one of the audience
members asked about
another company,
which is their competitors,
and said that they have a huge reputation
and huge resources, this competitor.
So what is this word, reputation?
Reputation is important.
A person can have a reputation, but
a company can also have a reputation.
Now, reputation means the way
that other people talk about you.
Okay, so he has a good reputation
means people say good things about him.
Right.
Or the media like newspapers and
websites, they say good things about him.
But if you have a bad reputation, it means
people are saying bad things about you.
Right.
Okay, so that pretty much
sums it up, a reputation.
What other people say about
you or how other people see you?
So maybe if a company
like this has a huge
reputation, it means that
it's very well respected
and people talk very good thing and
people talk well about this company.
That's right.
All right.
Now, another question
came along and they wanted
to know a little bit
more about the technical
details of this product
that they are introducing.
And Mr. Ford said that,
you know what, right
now we don't really
have time, but I'm going
to leave all the technical
specs on this PowerPoint
presentation and
you can look at it later.
Okay, so specs.
This is something you'll hear very,
very often, especially in technical areas.
But it means specifications for details.
So maybe I have a
computer and I know it's
an IBM computer, but
I don't know the specs.
I don't have the details.
So that's something that you
would want to find out if you have
a problem or you want to look
into it more closely and so specs.
That's right.
Okay.
So these are the specs.
Now, why don't we take a break.
Let's take a look at our dialogue
again and we'll be back in a bit.
Well, everyone, I'm
sure you'd like to join
me in thanking Michael for what
was a really inspirational presentation.
I see your thanks, Michael.
Now I'm sure many of
you will be keen to ask
some questions, so I'd like
to open up a Q&A session.
Please raise your hand if
you have any questions at all.
Yes, Janice.
Go ahead.
Yes.
Thank you, Jonathan.
I would just like to go
back to the comment
Mr. Ford made in regards to our
competitors, particularly orange.
Now, as you know,
orange has established
themselves as the market leader
in the high-end laptop market.
How does Mr. Ford expect
to compete with a company
that has such a huge
reputation and huge resources?
Well, Janice, first of all,
thanks for a very good question.
I think you have hit the
nail on the head, actually.
Orange are the global leaders
precisely because of their size and power.
But although we can't
compete in terms of
size, I believe we hold an advantage in
terms of dedication to customer service.
Yes, Sidemen, this is a
David and Goliath battle.
But don't forget who won that contest.
Mr. Ford, could you elaborate on actual
technical details of the X420 a little more?
I'd love to, but I think we're a
little pressed for time right now.
However, Jonathan is
all the technical specs
for you on the PowerPoint presentation,
which you can look over in your own time.
Mr. Ford, one final question.
Would you like to join me
for a game of golf this Sunday?
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at some
of those phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
The first phrase we have here is one
that I really like and I use very often.
I think you have hit the nail on the head.
That's right.
To hit the nail on the head.
So this is a very common
phrase, which basically
means I think you
got it exactly right.
Okay, so think about
a nail that you're
hammering something you
have a hammer in your hand.
It's very easy to miss.
But boom, when you
hit it, hit the nail on
the head, it means
you have it exactly right.
That's right.
So this was actually a
response to one of the
questions because it was a very
good question and it had a valid point.
So this is why Mr. Ford said
you hit the nail on the head.
This is exactly right.
I completely agree with you.
After that, though, we
had this interesting phrase,
he said, I admit this is a
David and Goliath battle.
Okay, so now this is obviously
he's speaking metaphorically, right?
That's right.
So David and Goliath, that's actually
a story that we often talk about.
It's a biblical story.
So it comes from Christianity
and David and Goliath fought.
But David was very, very small
and Goliath was a monster.
He was very huge.
And so everyone said Goliath will
win the fight, but David won the fight.
And so this is an example or a story that
people often use when they say, listen, it
may be the case that you
think the big giants will win.
But actually the small man
or our small company will win.
That's right.
As you said, we many
times make reference to
this, even not in the biblical
sense, but it's just the size.
Maybe we're a small company.
We're going to fight this big company.
So we say it's a David and Goliath
battle, or even athletes, maybe two boxers.
One is bigger than the other.
So they'll say it's a David
and Goliath boxing match.
That's right.
Okay.
Now when we got the questions about
the technical details of the computer, Mr.
Ford said that we are a little
bit pressed for time right now.
That's why we can't
really answer that question.
That's right.
And so to be pressed for time
means that you don't have a lot of time.
You are in a rush.
That's right.
So if you are pressed for time,
you don't have too much time.
You can't.
You're in a hurry, basically.
So I can say, hey, Marco,
can you come here
and look at this thing
on my computer, please?
I'm sorry.
I'm a little bit pressed
for time right now.
I'll take a look at it in an hour.
Okay.
So those are all of our
phrases from Fluency Builder.
Let's take another listen to our
dialogue and we'll be right back.
Well everyone, I'm sure you'd
like to join me in thanking
Michael for what was a really
inspirational presentation.
Since here, thanks, Michael.
Now I'm sure many of you will
be keen to ask some questions.
So I'd like to open up a Q&A session.
Please raise your hand if
you have any questions at all.
Yes, Janice.
Go ahead.
Yes.
Thank you, Jonathan.
I would just like to go
back to the comment
Mr. Ford made in regards to our
competitors, particularly orange.
Now, as you know,
orange has established
themselves as the market leader
in the high-end laptop market.
How does Mr. Ford expect
to compete with a company
that has such a huge
reputation and huge resources?
Well, Janice, first of all,
thanks for a very good question.
I think you have hit the
nail on the head, actually.
Orange are the global leaders,
precisely because of their size and power.
But although we can't
compete in terms of
size, I believe we hold an advantage in
terms of dedication to customer service.
Yes, Sidemen, this is a
David and Goliath battle.
But don't forget who won that contest.
Mr. Ford, could you elaborate on actual
technical details of the X420 a little more?
I'd love to, but I think we're a
little pressed for time right now.
However, Jonathan is
all the technical specs
for you on the PowerPoint presentation,
which you can look over in your own time.
Mr. Ford, one final question.
Would you like to join me
for a game of golf this Sunday?
All right, so that was part 10 of our
10 part series about presentations.
We took a look at many
different aspects where
you can take it as an
example as we talked
about computers and
marketing, but you can
more or less have an
idea of how a presentation
should go and the type
of vocab you can use.
That's right, and I
think that this particular
dialogue today was
very, very useful because
a lot of times you're
going to have people
asking you questions
and filling in details.
So you can use some
of these phrases to help
explain exactly what your presentation
was about when people do have questions.
That's right.
So we hope that you enjoyed this series and
we would like to hear from you if you have
any other suggestions
about a series of
dialogues or a series of
lessons that we can do.
We had one about a
job interview, all the
steps and everything, how
a job interview would go.
We just had a series
about presentations, so
maybe you can give us some feedback or
some ideas of what you would like to learn.
Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you there.
Bye.